# 今天買了一些那些
Today I've bought some kind of,
# 雞 鴨 鵝
chickens, ducks, geese,
# 公雞
and roosters,
# 都有
everything.
# 買點回來這裡放養一下
I took them all back and let them run around here.
# 這 草好多啦 這裡
Here, here's a lot of grass.
# 把它們放出來
I let them come out first.
# 先放這個 這個我也不知道是甚麼
This bag first. I don't even know what they are?
# 看一下才知道
I need to take a look.
# 哎呀 這是鵝
Aya! These are geese!
# 鵝用來看家
I'll keep them as watchgeese.
# 你看 這兩個鵝
Look! These two geese
# 哎呀
Aya!
# 夠大吧
Really big, aren't they?
# 一下來就拉屎
It poops once it comes out.
# 好大
Really big!
# 鴨子
Ducks
# 這個
These are,
# 這個也是鴨子哦
these are also ducks.
# 那麼多隻
So many ducks
# 這兩個 這兩個也是鵝
These two, these two are geese too.
# 我要是買小的
If I bought the small ones,
# 小的長 長大太難啦
the small ones, the small ones would grow too slowly.
# 還不如直接買大的
So why not simply buy the big ones?
# 想吃的時候就直接進來拎
Whenever I want something to eat, I can simply come in and take one right away.
# 這4隻鴨子
These are four ducks.
# 一共多少隻
How many are there in total?
# 一共10隻
Ten ducks in total
# 這小雞
These are chickens.
# 這雞太小
The chickens are too small.
# 現在不能吃
I don't think I can eat them now.
# 這樣的小雞
They are far too tiny!
# 知道就不買 知道就不買這個
I wouldn't, I wouldn't have bought them had I known it in advance.
# 太小啦
Too small!
# 買大的
I should buy the big ones.
# 你看 這個 笨啊
Look! They are, stupid!
# 好笨這雞
Stupid chickens!
# 特意買了一個
Specially for the chickens, I've prepared a,
# 公的
rooster.
# 嗯 這個公雞
Um! This is a rooster.
# 這公雞
This rooster,
# 夠大的哦 三四斤哦
is big enough. It's almost two kilograms, you know.
# 會不會飛
Can it fly?
# 會飛喲
Yea, it can.
# 啊 這小雞
Ah! These small chickens,
# 小雞崽
baby chickens
# 你看 它這個小雞
Look! These small chickens,
# 那麼小
they're so small.
# 開始它慢慢開始找 找東西吃啦
They start, they're starting to look, look for food.
# 看一下那個鵝
Let's have a look at the geese.
# 那個鵝很靚哦
The geese are really beautiful.
# 好吵啊 它們
They're so noisy!
# 應該會下蛋哦 這個 那麼大的
I think they lay egg, don't they? They're already that big now.
# 不好抓 怕我
I can't catch them. They're scared of me.
# 來都不來一下
They don't even come to me.
# 沒餵它們 今天不能餵哦
Cuz I haven't fed them. But I'm not supposed to feed them today.
# 要明天開始餵
I have to wait till tomorrow.
# 給它們吃下草就行啦
They can simply have some grass.
# 你看 這兩個鵝
Look! These two geese...
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 它不肯啊
It doesn't like it.
# 那麼不聽話
You're so naughty!
# 它吃草的 這個
It eats grass, this one.
# 那吃點草 這裡有草
Alright, then have some grass. Here's some grass.
# 它不吃
It's not eating.
# 好啦 我不打擾你啦
Alright! I'm not gonna disturb you anymore.
# 我不抓你啦 嗯 哎喲
I'll leave you alone. Um! Ayo!
# 這是 肯定是公的
This is, it must be male.
# 那麼兇
It's so fierce.
# 好兇啊 這個鵝
It's really fierce, this goose.
# 養鵝的話肯定 額 可以防一下那個 黃鼠狼
Keeping geese can certainly, I mean, can prevent the weasels from coming.
# 這邊黃鼠狼的話 它肯定就不敢來
The weasels nearby certainly don't dare to come,
# 因為有我
because of the geese.
# 看那小雞 保護那些小雞
Have a look at the chickens. They protect the chickens.
# 全跑啦
They've all run away.
# 你看它們 被我嚇到它們啦
Look! They're all scared by me.
# 今天兄弟又送一些狗給我
My buddy gave me some puppies again today.
# 我都養不起我自己啦
I can't even afford my own food now.
# 還送給我
But he still gave me puppies.
# 在那邊 我們去看一下
They're over there. Let's go and have a look!
# 鵝就放在這邊啦 不管它們啦
I'll leave the geese here alone.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個寵物狗
This is a pet dog.
# 就是兄弟送的
They are from my buddy.
# 養不大的 你看 路這個一模一樣的
They won't get big. Look! He just looks exactly the same as this dog.
# 長大了就跟這樣
This will be how he looks like when he grows up.
# 那麼 那麼
It's so, it's so,
# 那麼不好看
so ugly.
# 是不是
Am I right?
# 像不像你
Does he look like you?
# 像不像
Does he?
# 好像啊
Yea, of course!
# 看 長大了就不好看啦
As he grows up, he is now no longer cute.
# 你還小的時候好可愛哦
You were really cute when you were still a puppy.
# 爪子也很利
His claws are really sharp too.
# 你看
Look!
# 這小狗
This puppy...
# 哎呀 夠大
Aya! He's big.
# 這些好像漂亮一點哦
These seem to be prettier.
# 你看 這個
Look! This one,
# 這好像不一樣的
this one seems to be a bit different.
# 這個好靚 這個
This is beautiful, this one.
# 你看 這個
Look! This one...
# 看一下你
Let me have a look at you.
# 哎呀 這個好靚 這個
Aya! This is really beautiful, this one.
# 你看
Look!
# 這個靚 這個
She's beautiful, isn't she?
# 它爪子好長啊 爪子
Her claws are really long, her claws.
# 這個爪子好 好長
The claws are really, really long.
# 嗯 走開一點
Um! Go 'way!
# 這個也靚 這個
This is also beautiful, this one.
# 你看 這個
Look! This one...
# 這個靚
this one is beautiful.
# 要不就放在這裡吧
Shall I just leave them here?
# 全部放到這裡
Yea, leave them all here.
# 所以
So,
# 哪個粉絲想要的 這來 這來
any fans want them? Come here, come here,
# 自提哦
and pick one.
# 發快遞發不了的
I can't courier them to you.
# 誰要就誰帶回去
Whoever wants them can come and take home with you.
# 暫時先放到我這裡養著
They'll be staying here with me for the time being.
# 還有獠牙
He even has tusks.
# 好可愛哦
So cute!
# 很聽話的哦
He's a very good puppy, you know.
# 誰要誰拿去
Come and take him with you.
# 嗯 這隻怎麼那麼瘦 這個
Um? Why is this one so skinny, this one.
# 嘴巴好大啦 很能吃的哦 這樣的狗
She has a very big mouth! A puppy with a such a big mouth is always a big eater.
# 一臉無辜的看著我
She stares at me with her eyes filled with innocence.
# 沒事
No worries.
# 這兩隻好靚 這兩隻
These two are really beautiful, these two.
# 藍眼睛
Blue eyes
# 黑鼻子
Black nose
# 很靚的哦 這兩隻哦
These two are really really beautiful.
# 它毛好乾淨啊
His coat is very clean.
# 要天天給它洗澡才行
I'll need to bathe him every day.
# 它這個毛 跟 跟原來不一樣的 比較長的這個毛 (註︰「原來」應該是指其他，但我不幫他詮釋了)
His hair is, is, is different from the original one. His hair is a bit longer.
# 心跳得好快呀 生怕我不要它
His heart is beating very fast. He worries that I might throw him away.
# 要你
I won't.
# 小狗
Puppy
# 好靚呀 它這個小狗
It's really beautiful, this puppy.
# 好無辜的眼神
A pair of eyes full of innocence
# 兄弟不要它啦
My buddy doesn't want them anymore.
# 不要我要
I'll have them.
# 還養得起你們
I can still afford having you guys.
# 你看
Look!
# 很乖呀
A good puppy
# 全部躲到這裡面來啦
They're all hiding over there.
# 給點東西給它吃一下
Let me give them some food.
# 你看 這個狗都跟他們玩
Look! This dog likes being with them.
# 總共8條哦
There are eight in total.
# 8條
Eight puppies
# 放在這裡先
Let them stay here first,
# 看誰要的
and see who wants them.
# 誰要的把它領回去
Anyone who wants them, come and take one with you.
# 額 點給果子給你們吃
Eh! I have some fruits for you.
# 要不要
You want some?
# 吃草的 這個狗
He eats grass, this puppy.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 耳朵不一樣的 你看 這個
Their ears are not the same. Look! This one.
# 小時候很可愛的
He was really cute when he was small.
# 長大了成這樣子啦
But that's how he looks now.